Akemi Homura, time traveler.
By turning back time
and changing past events,
you have relived this past month over and over across numerous different timelines,
seeking the outcome you desire.
Your existence has answered at least one great mystery:
Why does Kaname Madoka possess such great potential as a magical girl?
Now I can put together a reasonable hypothesis.
You see, a magical girl's latent potential
is based on the weight of the
karmic destiny she bears.
I could have understood if she had been the queen or savior of a country,
but I couldn't comprehend why Madoka,
who led only an ordinary life,
should have so many threads of fate woven so tightly around her.
But listen, Homura.
Isn't it possible that Madoka became more powerful as a magical girl
every time you reset the timeline?
I thought so. You were the cause.
Or should I call it a side effect of your magic?
What do you mean?
You traveled through time for just one purpose: to protect Kaname Madoka.
By turning back time over and over,
each time for the same reason and goal,
you inadvertently caused multiple timelines to converge together
and centered them all on Kaname Madoka.
If Madoka's threads of fate from each of those separate timelines
all ended up linking to the
Madoka in this current timeline,
that would explain why her magical potential appears so impossibly huge.
All the karmic destiny you sent spinning across all of those different timelines
eventually attached to Kaname Madoka.
After all, everything you did was for her.
Excellent work, Homura.
You've raised Madoka to be the most powerful witch we've ever seen.
I'll never forget the promises we exchanged
I still see it when I close my eyes
I'll move forward as I cast off
this darkness engulfing me
How long will it be before
I see that lost future again?
I'll walk upon this Earth,
and pierce this shadowy veil of unease,
as many times as necessary
The clock that's endlessly ticked away
now tells of the beginning
Let's open the once-closed door,
with these unwavering feelings
My heart started racing once again to paint the future
Even if I get stuck in a maze,
the beautiful blue sky will always be waiting for me
So I won't be afraid
No matter what happens next, I won't give in
The one thing I have left to guide me
Episode 11
Sayaka Miki's Funeral
The body of Mitakihara Junior High
second-year Miki Sayaka,
who had been missing since
the 12th of this month,
Miki
was discovered today in a
room at a downtown hotel.
As there were no signs of a struggle present at the scene,
the police have not ruled out either murder or accidental death in their investigation.
Up next is the weather forecast.
Tonight, expect moderate winds from the northwest accompanied by rain.
Welcome back.
Hey, Madoka.
About Sayaka...
You really don't know anything
about what happened?
Yeah.
Sayaka and Kyouko are both dead.
It's not really that surprising.
The signs had been there for quite some time.
So you're saying you don't care?
Even though you practically caused their deaths?
Tell me, do you ever feel guilty about what happens to livestock?
Do you ever think about how their meat ends up on your table?
Stop it!
That's not a rational reaction.
If you found that vision to be cruel,
then you're not seeing the whole picture.
In exchange for one day
becoming food for humans,
livestock are provided for all their lives and sheltered from natural selection.
Cows, pigs, and chickens all have far higher rates of reproduction in captivity than in the wild.
Wouldn't you call that the
ideal symbiotic relationship?
Are you trying to say we're the same?
Actually, we're far more accommodating
toward humanity than you are with livestock.
Though we're not perfect at it,
we at least negotiate with you as sentient beings.
You don't believe me?
How about I show you, then?
I'll show you the history that mankind has spent together with the Incubators.
We have been involved with your civilization since before your recorded history.
Countless girls throughout history have formed contracts with Incubators,
had their wishes granted, and
ultimately succumbed to despair.
That which begins with a prayer of hope ends with a curse of despair.
Such is the cycle that countless
magical girls have repeated to this day.
Some changed history forever, and elevated
your society to new stages of development.
Stop it already!
They trusted you, and you betrayed them!
It was not we who betrayed them,
but rather their own wishes.
No matter what their hopes were,
anything that goes beyond reason
will without fail cause some sort of distortion.
It's only natural that this would result in disaster.
If you consider a natural consequence like that to be "betrayal,"
then their mistake was to make those wishes in the first place.
Not that I am calling them foolish.
It can't be denied that their sacrifices have shaped human history.
The current standard of living you enjoy was made possible by all those tears shed in the past.
If you understand that, then how can you be so obsessed with the lives of a select few?
Did you really feel nothing while watching over those girls this whole time?
Didn't you at least try to understand how much they were suffering?
If we could, we wouldn't have come all
the way to this planet in the first place.
In our society,
the phenomenon known as "emotion" is
nothing more than a rare mental disorder.
That's why we were surprised when we found you humans.
We never imagined a world could exist where each individual possessed its own set of emotions
and still managed to coexist with others.
If none of you had ever come to this planet...
You'd probably still be living in caves.
It really does hurt, losing one
of my own students this way.
Yeah. We still don't even know what really happened.
One of the third-years is apparently missing as well.
Our staff meeting was a complete mess.
I guess nobody knows anything, do they?
It sounds like Sayaka had some trouble with a friend over a boy.
She's taking all this pretty hard as well.
Ordinarily, it'd blow over leaving behind a few bittersweet memories, but since it ended like this...
The police are going to rule it accidental death,
exacerbated by mental stress after running away from home.
They don't have any leads to go on.
How's Madoka taking it?
I have no idea.
My gut tells me she knows
something about all this.
But it doesn't seem like
she's lying to me either.
This is the first time I haven't been
able to tell what she's really thinking.
Pathetic, right? I don't know what my own daughter is up to.
I never thought I'd see you at such a loss.
Lately, something has seemed
a little off about her.
I can tell something's
weighing on her mind.
but she hasn't come to talk
to me about it like usual.
I thought she knew she
could always rely on me...
It's hard with kids that age.
You turn around one day,
and suddenly they're all grown up.
It must be a pretty big
shock for the parents.
I guess you're right.
At this point, you just
need to believe in her.
I'm sure what Madoka needs most right now is some time to sort out her feelings.
You need to give her some space.
It's so hard not being able to do anything.
That's the Junko I've always known.
Akemi Homura
May I come in?
Is that... the Walpurgisnacht?
Kyouko told me about it.
She said the two of you were teaming up to take down a witch neither of you could handle alone.
You've been preparing for it this whole time, haven't you?
Will the city be in danger?
Unlike the witches you've seen so far,
this one doesn't need to hide itself within a barrier.
If it manifests even once, thousands will die.
Since ordinary people can't see it,
they'll think the destruction was caused by an
earthquake, tornado, or other natural disaster.
So it absolutely has to be stopped, right?
Now that Kyouko's... dead too...
you're the only magical girl
left who can fight it, so I—
I can do it on my own.
Sakura Kyouko may not have been able to defeat the Walpurgisnacht alone, but I can.
I never really needed Kyouko's
assistance to begin with.
I just agreed so she wouldn't lose face.
Really?
I don't get it...
I want to believe you.
I don't want to think you'd lie to me.
And yet, I just can't believe you're really going to be all right.
I just can't believe what you're saying is true.
I don't know how to tell you what I really feel.
Homura...
Because...
I'm not even living in the same time as you!
You see, I... I came from the future.
I've met you over and over again,
and each and every time,
I've had to watch you die.
How can I save you?
How can I change your fate?
I've gone back in time over and over again, searching for that answer.
That means... Huh?
I'm sorry.
I must sound crazy, right?
I must be creeping you out.
To you, I'm just some transfer
student you met a month ago.
But to me...
To me, you are...
The more I repeat all this, the further in time we drift from one another.
Our feelings also drift further apart,
and my words don't reach you anymore.
The truth is, I think I lost
myself a long time ago.
Homura...
I will save you.
That was all I had in mind
when I began this.
And now that I've come this far,
it's the one thing I have left to guide me.
It's all right if you don't understand.
It's all right if my words don't reach you.
But please...
I beg of you.
Let me protect you.
Akemi Homura
These thunderclouds are spreading
and rotating at unbelievable speeds.
It's a clear sign that a supercell is forming!
Issue an evacuation order at once!
An evacuation order has been issued as of 7AM this morning due to urgent weather conditions.
All residents must immediately evacuate to the nearest shelter.
This is the Mitakihara Municipal Office.
An evacuation order...
It's coming.
Is this a sleepover?
Are we camping?
That's right. We're all camping here tonight!
Homura...
This time...
I'll finish it once and for all.
What's wrong, Madoka?
I-I need to use the bathroom.
Is it true that Homura can win by herself?
Even if I said no, would you believe me?
There's no point in me
trying to convince you now.
See for yourself.
See just how far she can get against the Walpurgisnacht.
Why does she push herself so hard to fight?
Because she still hasn't given up hope.
If it comes down to it, I'm sure she'll nullify this timeline like the others, and continue fighting.
She'll continue to repeat this meaningless chain of events, failures be damned.
At this point, it's no longer possible for her to stop or give up.
The moment she believes that everything was pointless, that your fate cannot be changed,
Akemi Homura will succumb to
despair and become a Grief Seed.
She knows that all too well.
That's why she doesn't have a choice.
She must continue to fight,
even if she has no chance of winning.
So you're saying that as long as she
continues to hope, she can't be saved?
That's right.
Just like every other magical
girl throughout history.
Madoka, you saw it too, didn't you?
But...
But!
Where do you think you're going?
Mom.
I have to go save my friend—
Leave that to the firefighters.
We civilians have to stay put.
It has to be me!
You're not the only person in this world!
Do you even know how much
the people around you—
I know!
I really do understand.
I love you too, Mom. Dad too.
I know how much you all care about me.
I know I need to value my own life.
But this is different.
It's because you're all so important to me that I have to protect you.
That's exactly why... there's
somewhere I have to be right now!
And you can't tell me what this is about?
Take me with you, then.
I can't.
Stay with Dad and Tatsuya.
Don't make them worry about you.
You said I grew up to be a good girl, right?
That I don't lie and I don't do anything bad.
Do you still believe that?
Will you trust that what I'm doing is right?
Are you certain you're not making a mistake?
You're not being misled by anyone's lies?
That's right.
Thank you, Mom.
If I let it get any further...
it'll reach the shelter.
Whatever happens, I have to stop it right here!
No way...
Why...
Why can't I beat it, no matter how many times I try?!
If I do this again, I'll only add to Madoka's karmic burden.
In the end, everything I've done has...
That's enough.
You've done enough, Homura.
Madoka...
Don't tell me you're...
Homura, I'm sorry.
One day the light of love burning in your eyes
will transcend time
and destroy one of this world's dreams
as it spirals toward the apocalypse
What is it that you seek
now that you're done hesitating?
Is there a glimpse of hope for tomorrow
beyond this greedy admiration?
I want to be armed with the power
to shatter even the darkness in my hand,
just like the ancient magic in my childhood dreams,
the next time I see your innocent smile.
In my trembling hands I hold
the courage of a plucked flower
My feelings are all I can rely on;
the prayer that awakens
the light
Illustrated by   Buriki
If someone says it's wrong to have hope,
I will tell them they're wrong every single time.
I know my determination will never waver.
My very best friend
Finale
My very best friend.